{"tossups":[{"question":"In this discipline, the word “brisure” [brih-ZHOOR] refers to small marks that are used for purposes of “cadency.” Rare adjectives used in this discipline include “coward,” “tricorporated,” and “addorsed.” The corrupted form “hatchment” is no longer commonly used in this field, having been replaced with the word “achievement.” The word (*) “rampant” was originally used in this discipline to refer to a common attitude. As a result of French influence, adjectives are often placed after nouns in the distinctive syntax of this discipline’s “blazons,” which are descriptions such as “Gules [goolz], three lions passant [PASS-int] guardant [GARD-int] in pale or armed and langued [lang’d] azure.” For 10 points, name this discipline involving the design of coats of arms and related symbols.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>heraldry<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>heraldic<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"<b><u>heraldry<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>heraldic<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Other Academic","subcategory":"Other Academic","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":1},{"question":"An approach whose name starts with this word was criticized by Jim Sinclair in a 1999 essay which notes that it’s possible to wear a blue shirt one day and a yellow shirt the next day. A phrase starting with this word is favored over terms that imply “defeat” or “passivity” in the Denver Principles, which were co-written by the activist Bobbi Campbell. A phrase starting with this word is commonly shortened to (*) PWS by speech-language pathologists. Identity-first language is contrasted with an approach that foregrounds this word to emphasize the humanity of an individual with a disability, rather than emphasizing their disability. For 10 points, name this synonym for “individuals.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>people<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>people<\/b><\/u>-first language or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u>-first language or <b><u>people<\/b><\/u> (living) with AIDS or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u> (living) with AIDS or <b><u>people<\/b><\/u> who stutter or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u> who stutters]","answer":"<b><u>people<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>people<\/b><\/u>-first language or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u>-first language or <b><u>people<\/b><\/u> (living) with AIDS or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u> (living) with AIDS or <b><u>people<\/b><\/u> who stutter or <b><u>person<\/b><\/u> who stutters]","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Visual Fine Arts","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":2},{"question":"A portmanteau that combines this word and the word “sad” was coined by Rebecca Reid in response to a Kendall Jenner post about acne. The movie that introduced this word inspired a TV series in which a rotating series of hosts, including Nick Young and Elle King, briefly replaced the original co-host, Max Joseph. This word was coined in a 2010 documentary by Henry (*) Joost and Ariel Schulman that follows the latter’s brother Nev and his relationship with a woman named Megan. This word was further popularized by the story of Lennay Kekua, the subject of a hoax perpetrated on the Notre Dame football player Manti Te’o [MAN-tye TEH-oh]. For 10 points, name this slang term for the act of deceiving someone by creating a fake persona on a social networking service.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>catfish<\/b><\/u>ing [prompt on <u>fish<\/u>ing before the occurrence of “word” in “the movie that introduced this word”]","answer":"<b><u>catfish<\/b><\/u>ing [prompt on fishing before the occurrence of “word” in “the movie that introduced this word”]","category":"History","subcategory":"European History","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":3},{"question":"This poet got into an argument with a friend who complained about the vulgarity of this poet’s use of the term “water-closet” in a poem describing a statue of Christ and St. Peter with a rooster. This author wrote that everything in the Bible is “only connected by ‘and’ and ‘and’” in the poem “Over 2,000 Illustrations and a Complete Concordance.” In another poem by this author, someone sends a message to “high-strung (*) automobiles” by arranging “rows of cans” to spell “ESSO—SO—SO—SO.” A typo for the word “mammoth” inspired the poem “The Man-Moth” from her collection North & South. For 10 points, what poet of “Filling Station” wrote that “the art of losing isn’t hard to master” in her poem “One Art”?","formatted_answer":"Elizabeth <b><u>Bishop<\/b><\/u>","answer":"Elizabeth <b><u>Bishop<\/b><\/u>","category":"Literature","subcategory":"American Literature","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":4},{"question":"One of the earliest written uses of this word, though spelled with an extra letter, is in a poem about the moon landing by W. H. Auden. The advertising writer Howie Krakow thought this was the funniest word in the world, according to John Swartzwelder, who first learned this word from Krakow. A library clerk says this word in response to the line “I thought it was a secret ballot” after giving a character the complete results of a local mayoral election. This word, which may be of (*) Yiddish origin, is spelled out for emphasis by Lisa to express her reaction to the idea of going to Blockoland in the Simpsons episode “Hungry, Hungry Homer,” which popularized this interjection. For 10 points, name this three-letter expression of indifference.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>meh<\/b><\/u> (Auden spelled it “mneh.”)","answer":"<b><u>meh<\/b><\/u> (Auden spelled it “mneh.”)","category":"Science","subcategory":"Chemistry","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":5},{"question":"The prefixes “über” and “unter” were added to this word by a pair of scientists who proposed a discriminant equal to “m squared over a to the 3/2 power, multiplied by k,” denoted lambda. A portmanteau which combines this word with a term from math describes things which are the subject of the Chamberlin-Moulton hypothesis. A phrase abbreviated (*) SSSB was first defined alongside this word. Alan Stern has criticized a definition of this word whose prominent defenders include Steven Soter and Mike Brown. The requirement of “clearing the neighborhood” was incorporated into a definition of this word adopted in 2006 by the IAU. For 10 points, name this word which only describes eight bodies in the Solar System since Pluto’s demotion.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>planet<\/b><\/u>s (The portmanteau is “planetesimal.” SSSB stands for “small Solar System body.”)","answer":"<b><u>planet<\/b><\/u>s (The portmanteau is “planetesimal.” SSSB stands for “small Solar System body.”)","category":"Science","subcategory":"Other Science","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":6},{"question":"With vowels on the x-axis, this syllable that ends with a vowel is the bottom-left-most entry on the standard gojūon [goh-joo-ohn] chart of kana [kah-nah]. This syllable refers to a key value in Japanese culture that is generally translated as “harmony.” This syllable is also the Japanese pronunciation of the oldest attested Chinese name for Japan. In the evening counterpart of the morning greeting ohayō [Ohio], this syllable follows (*) konban [kohn-bahn]. The Japanese subject particle ga [gah] is contrasted with a topic particle consisting of this syllable, which follows watashi [wah-tah-shee] in a phrase used to introduce oneself. For 10 points, what Japanese syllable, which begins with a semivowel pronounced with rounded lips, follows konnichi [koh-nee-chee] in a common greeting?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>wa<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>wa<\/b><\/u>","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":7},{"question":"One name for this place was established in 1613 to honor the consortium of livery companies who built a walled city at this site during a colonization process known as a “plantation.” To avoid naming themselves after this place, some local businesses name themselves after the River Foyle instead. After this place’s city council was renamed in 1984, the DUP and (*) UUP boycotted meetings of the council. The longer of the two common names for this place appears in the name of an “air” whose melody is used in the song “Danny Boy.” Whether you use the mnemonic FAT DAD or FAT LAD for the six counties depends on which name you prefer for this place. For 10 points, name this city and county in Northern Ireland whose longer name, beginning with “London,” is favored by unionists.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Derry<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Londonderry<\/b><\/u>; accept “<b><u>Londonderry<\/b><\/u> Air”]","answer":"<b><u>Derry<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Londonderry<\/b><\/u>; accept “<b><u>Londonderry<\/b><\/u> Air”]","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Auditory Fine Arts","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":8},{"question":"An assistant to this person invented the Tironian [tee-ROH-nee-in] notes, one of the earliest systems of shorthand. A treatise by Erasmus subtitled “A Dialogue on the Best Style of Speaking” attacks those who insist on imitating this person’s vocabulary. A word for a knowledgeable guide derives, via Italian, from this person’s name. 18th-century Enlightenment authors particularly admired this coiner of the words (*) qualitas [KWAH-lee-toss] and humanitas [hoo-MAH-nee-toss] for transforming Latin into a sophisticated literary language. This person’s cognomen [cog-NOH-min] comes from the Latin for “chickpea,” and his nomen [NOH-min] is sometimes anglicized as “Tully.” For 10 points, name this Roman statesman who was targeted in the Catiline [CAT-uh-line] conspiracy and delivered the Philippics [fih-LIP-iks].","formatted_answer":"Marcus Tullius <b><u>Cicero<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>Tully<\/b><\/u> before “Tully”]","answer":"Marcus Tullius <b><u>Cicero<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>Tully<\/b><\/u> before “Tully”]","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":9},{"question":"A word in this language meaning “all pull together” has been proposed to actually come from a chant with which Indian railroad workers honored Durga. The activist Ronald McKinley Everett adopted a name from this language and coined a word based on a phrase meaning “first fruits” in this language. This language’s word for “books” is vitabu [vee-TAH-boo], because it borrowed the Arabic word kitab [kee-TAB] and reanalyzed the first syllable as the noun (*) class prefix ki [kee], which is pluralized as vi [vee]. A word for “extended family” in this language refers to a socialist ideology outlined in the Arusha [ah-ROO-shah] Declaration. The Disney character Simba is named after this language’s word for “lion.” For 10 points, name this Bantu language which is a lingua franca in much of Africa.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Swahili<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Kiswahili<\/b><\/u>] (The first clue is about the etymology of “Harambee.” The second clue is about Maulana Karenga, who coined the word “Kwanzaa.”)","answer":"<b><u>Swahili<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Kiswahili<\/b><\/u>] (The first clue is about the etymology of “Harambee.” The second clue is about Maulana Karenga, who coined the word “Kwanzaa.”)","category":"History","subcategory":"World History","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":10},{"question":"The title of one of this director’s films now means “turtleneck” in this director’s native language. A film by this director, in which a peacock perching on a fountain unfurls its tail during a snowfall, is the source of a word meaning “nostalgic memory” in that language. In a film by this director, the clairvoyant Maya writes the nonsense words (*) “asa nisi masa” on a chalkboard, triggering a flashback to the protagonist’s childhood. A dialectal word meaning “I remember” provides the title of this director’s film about Titta’s coming-of-age under fascism. The word “paparazzi” is a reference to a character in a 1960 film by this director which stars Anita Ekberg and Marcello Mastroianni. For 10 points, name this director of Amarcord, La Dolce Vita [lah DOHL-chay VEE-tah] and 8½.","formatted_answer":"Federico <b><u>Fellini<\/b><\/u>  Note to players: Your answer should be three consonants in the English alphabet.","answer":"Federico <b><u>Fellini<\/b><\/u>  Note to players: Your answer should be three consonants in the English alphabet.","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Other Fine Arts","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":11},{"question":"This three-consonant root is used in the name of the Canaanite god of dusk, the counterpart of the dawn god Shahar. A Bible character whose name combines a word for “father” with this root declares “I have no son to keep my name in remembrance” and therefore builds a pillar as a monument to himself. This root, whose basic meaning is “complete” or “safe,” is used in the name of a Bible character also called (*) Jedidiah. This root is the origin of the second half of the name of a city known as “al-Quds” [all-CUDS] in Arabic. This root is used in a word meaning “submission” which is the source of the name of a religion. For 10 points, name this three-consonant root used in Hebrew and Arabic words for “peace,” both of which are also used as greetings.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>S-L-M<\/b><\/u> (The words and names clued are, in order, Shalim, Absalom, Solomon/Shlomo, Jerusalem, Islam, and shalom/salaam.)","answer":"<b><u>S-L-M<\/b><\/u> (The words and names clued are, in order, Shalim, Absalom, Solomon/Shlomo, Jerusalem, Islam, and shalom/salaam.)","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":12},{"question":"This word describes “them rhymes you were kickin’” in a song that samples George Clinton’s “Atomic Dog” and several songs by Parliament. This word was misspelled on a belt worn by a singer in the video for the Rockwilder remix of another song. This word was originally a pejorative when it was used by Snoop Dogg on Dr. Dre’s song (*) “Fuck wit Dre Day.” This adjective was popularized by a song that samples Stevie Nicks’s “Edge of Seventeen” and appears on the 2001 album Survival. That song titled for this word repeatedly asks “Can you handle this?” For 10 points, name this portmanteau popularized by a Destiny’s Child song that proclaims “I don’t think you’re ready for this jelly.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>bootylicious<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>bootylicious<\/b><\/u>","category":"Trash","subcategory":"Trash","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":13},{"question":"A 1995 Jack Block paper about a theory of this concept discusses the jingle and jangle fallacies, which involve assuming that things are the same because they have the same names or different because they have different names. The acronym LOTS, referring to data used to study this concept, was coined by the psychologist who developed the 16PF questionnaire to study this concept, Raymond (*) Cattell. The acronym OCEAN refers to a set of factors used for describing this concept, including openness to experience and agreeableness. Temperament is distinguished from, for 10 points, what construct which is described by acronyms like “ESTP” and “INFJ” in the Myers-Briggs Type Indicator?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>personality<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>personality<\/b><\/u>","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":14},{"question":"In Canadian French, this word can refer to the antlers of a deer or moose. When Dr. King Schultz uses this French-derived word in Django Unchained, Calvin Candie does not understand it despite claiming to be a Francophile. A white object prominently worn by Henry IV of France is an example of the helmet (*) plumes to which this word originally referred. This is the last word of a play translated into English by both Brian Hooker and Anthony Burgess, in which a character who is dying from being hit on the head with a log declares that he has lost everything but this thing. This word was introduced to English by Edmond Rostand’s play Cyrano de Bergerac. For 10 points, name this synonym of “verve” or “flamboyance.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>panache<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>panache<\/b><\/u>","category":"Literature","subcategory":"World Literature","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":15},{"question":"One of these things was formerly called Bitaraplyk [bee-tah-RAH-plik], meaning “neutrality,” in a country whose permanent neutrality was recognized in 1995. Cassius Dio reports that some of these things were named “Amazonius” and “Invictus” in the 2nd century. John Brady mocked the names of some of these things by giving them nicknames like “Wheezy,” “Sneezy,” and “Freezy.” In 2002, some of these things were renamed after national symbols like (*) Alp Arslan and the Ruhnama by Saparmurat Niyazov [sah-par-muh-RAHT nee-YA-zov], the dictator of Turkmenistan. In an event named after one of these things whose name comes from the Greek for “summer heat,” Robespierre was arrested and executed. For 10 points, Brumaire and Thermidor were some of the seasonally-inspired names for what things in the French Republican calendar?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>month<\/b><\/u>s","answer":"<b><u>month<\/b><\/u>s","category":"History","subcategory":"European History","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":16},{"question":"This French-derived word displaced the Old English word bearnēacen [BARN-ah-cane]. This word is spelled the same as a French word for “meaningful” that was borrowed into German to mean “concise.” Informal synonyms for this word include “in the pudding club” and “up the spout.” This word describes a chad that has been dimpled even though all four corners are still attached. (*) “Gravid” is an uncommon technical synonym for this word. The French word enceinte [on-CENT] was used in an I Love Lucy episode title because CBS wouldn’t allow this word to be used. This is the English translation of the Spanish false friend embarazada [aim-bah-rah-SAH-dah]. For 10 points, name this word whose euphemistic synonyms include “in a family way” and “expecting.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>pregnant<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>pregnant<\/b><\/u> chad]","answer":"<b><u>pregnant<\/b><\/u> [accept <b><u>pregnant<\/b><\/u> chad]","category":"History","subcategory":"European History","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":17},{"question":"This is the second of the three words that structure Randy Olson’s narrative framework. The most common ASL sign for this word is the same as the sign for “different.” Paul Grice contrasted the sentence “Smith has left off beating his wife” with a sentence in which this word produces a conventional implicature; that sentence begins with the phrase “She was poor.” This word is the punchline of a classic Hegelbon tweet in which (*) Stephen A. Smith tells Skip Bayless “you KNOW I am sensitive to the Holocaust.” The Spanish translations of this word and the word “dog” form a minimal pair because the former has a plain R and the latter has a rolled R. This word is the “B” in the mnemonic “FANBOYS.” For 10 points, name this common coordinating conjunction.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>but<\/b><\/u> (Olson’s framework is called ABT, for “and-but-therefore.”)","answer":"<b><u>but<\/b><\/u> (Olson’s framework is called ABT, for “and-but-therefore.”)","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":18},{"question":"Michel Foucault wrote that, in this novel, “language breaks off its old kinship with things” and reappears “only as literature.” The first translation of this novel, by Thomas Shelton, is the source of the expression “pot calling the kettle black.” The surname of a fictional historian mentioned in this novel may be a pun on the word for “eggplant,” or may come from a phrase meaning (*) “son of the deer.” This novel’s story-within-a-story about a nobleman named Anselmo testing his wife’s fidelity is the origin of the word “lothario.” An illiterate character in this novel whose last name means “belly” in reference to his portliness often quotes proverbs known as sanchismos [sahn-CHEES-mohss]. For 10 points, name this novel which inspired the phrase “tilting at windmills.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Don Quixote<\/b><\/u> [or The Ingenious Gentleman <b><u>Don Quixote<\/b><\/u> of La Mancha or El ingenioso hidalgo <b><u>Don <\/b><\/u><b><u>Quijote<\/b><\/u> de la Mancha]","answer":"<b><u>Don Quixote<\/b><\/u> [or The Ingenious Gentleman <b><u>Don Quixote<\/b><\/u> of La Mancha or El ingenioso hidalgo <b><u>Don <\/b><\/u><b><u>Quijote<\/b><\/u> de la Mancha]","category":"Literature","subcategory":"European Literature","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":19},{"question":"James Fifield’s use of a slogan that follows the word “freedom” with this phrase is discussed in a Kevin M. Kruse book about “how corporate America invented Christian America.” Another usage of this phrase was first suggested by the Illinois lawyer Louis Albert Bowman. Because John Nicolay and John Hay’s drafts omit this phrase, some people are skeptical that this two-word phrase was used before the words (*) “shall have a new birth of freedom” in the last sentence of the Gettysburg Address. In 1951, the Knights of Columbus officially adopted the use of this two-word phrase, and on Flag Day in 1954, Dwight D. Eisenhower signed a bill adding this phrase to a text written by Francis Bellamy. For 10 points, name this phrase which follows “one Nation” in the Pledge of Allegiance.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>under God<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>under God<\/b><\/u>","category":"History","subcategory":"American History","packetNumber":3,"questionNumber":20}],"bonuses":[]}
